<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>bacchanalian madness</title>
    <link>https://brongulus.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on bacchanalian madness</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://brongulus.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://brongulus.github.io/about/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brongulus.github.io/about/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi! I&amp;rsquo;m Prashant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analog and Digital VLSI Design</title>
      <link>https://brongulus.github.io/notes/advd-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brongulus.github.io/notes/advd-notes/</guid>
      <description>Radio Spectrum  Used for communication initially Wireless communication Radio Spectrum is divided into frequency bands which are allocated to certain services. The band is subdivided into channels that are used for particular transmission. The wider the frequency bands and the channel, the more information that can be passed through them.    Frequency Use     VLF Maritime Navigation   LF Maritime Navigation   MF AM Radio   HF Shortwave Radio   VHF (30-300 MHz) TV, FM Radio   UHF (300 MHz - 3 GHz) TV, Mobile, GPS, Wi-FI, 4G   SHF Satellite   EHF Radio Astronomy     LF Bands provide wider coverage due to high penetration power but they have poor capacity (carry less information).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another nix post in the wall</title>
      <link>https://brongulus.github.io/blog/nix-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brongulus.github.io/blog/nix-intro/</guid>
      <description>Starting Are you using Nixos? This is not for you. Do you want multi-user installation? This is not for you. This is only useful if you want to use both flakes and home-manager.
  Single-user installation (no sudo needed, easier to remove, good for testing purposes)
 sh &amp;lt;(curl -L https://nixos.org/nix/install) --no-daemon   Source the new profile or login. . ~/.nix-profile/etc/profile.d/nix.sh
  Since most of the nix &amp;ldquo;guides&amp;rdquo; are outdated, check what your current version supports nix --help, at the time of writing this, there&amp;rsquo;s no need to enable experimental features for flakes :) spoke too soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combinatorial Mathematics</title>
      <link>https://brongulus.github.io/notes/combi-math/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brongulus.github.io/notes/combi-math/</guid>
      <description>General Counting Methods for Selection and Arrangement  Addition Principle: If there are \(r_1\) different objects in the first set, \(r_2\) different objects in the second set, . . . , and \(r_m\) different objects in the m^th set, and if the different sets are disjoint, then the number of ways to select an object from one of the m sets is \(r_1 +r_2 + · · · +r_m\). Multiplication Principle: Suppose a procedure can be broken into m successive (ordered) stages, with \(r_1\) different outcomes in the first stage, \(r_2\) different outcomes in the second stage,.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computation</title>
      <link>https://brongulus.github.io/notes/computation-das/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brongulus.github.io/notes/computation-das/</guid>
      <description>Simplicity Turing Machine  Infinite Tape: For memory purposes ....................BBBBBBBBBBBBBB................ ..........................^.......................   user.save() user.email = &amp;#34;alice@example.com&amp;#34; Lambda Calculus Limits - The Halting Problem Structure Turing Equivalence Finite State Machines Chomsky Hierarchy  Regex Recognize Python Recognize C++, JS etc Turing-equivalent  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a blog using ox-hugo, org mode and github pages</title>
      <link>https://brongulus.github.io/blog/blog-creation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brongulus.github.io/blog/blog-creation/</guid>
      <description>I was going to make a post explaining how I made this blog but it was rendered pretty useless by this. So yeah, I might archive this later.
  Install hugo from your package manager.
  Create a new site:
 hugo new site blog   Add a theme:
 cd blog  git init  git submodule add &amp;lt;theme_url&amp;gt; themes/&amp;lt;name&amp;gt;   Install ox-hugo in emacs</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differential Geometry</title>
      <link>https://brongulus.github.io/notes/dg-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brongulus.github.io/notes/dg-notes/</guid>
      <description>Theory of Space Curves Representation of space curves  Level Curve: f(x,y,z) = C From level curves to parametrized curves: \(y=x^{2} &amp;lt;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;&amp;gt; \gamma(t)=(\gamma_{1}(t),\gamma_{2}(t))\) Taking \(\gamma_{1}(t)=t\), we get \(\gamma_{2}(t)=t^{2}\) hence the parametrization is \(\gamma(t)=(t,t^{2})\) NOTE: Check if domain of x satisfies domain of t or not. That is, the same parametrisation can be represented as \((t^{2}.t^{4})\) or \((t^{3},t^{6})\) but only the latter is a correct representation. From parametrized curves to level curves: \(\gamma(t)=(cos^{3}t,sin^{3}t)\) &amp;lt;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;gt; F(x,y)=C; Using \(sin^{2}t+cos^{2}t=1\) we get, \(x^{2/3}+y^{2/3}=1\) as the level curve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IUSACO</title>
      <link>https://brongulus.github.io/notes/iusaco-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brongulus.github.io/notes/iusaco-notes/</guid>
      <description>Elementary techniques - Input and Output #include &amp;lt;cstdio&amp;gt;using namespace std; int main() {  freopen(&amp;#34;template.in&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;r&amp;#34;, stdin);  freopen(&amp;#34;template.out&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;w&amp;#34;, stdout); }  When using C++, arrays should be declared globally, or initialized to zeros if declared locally to avoid garbage values. 32bit int: \(\pm 2\times10^{9}\) v/s 64bit int: \(\pm 9\times10^{18}\)  Complexity and algorithm analysis </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meditations</title>
      <link>https://brongulus.github.io/blog/meditations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brongulus.github.io/blog/meditations/</guid>
      <description>Book 2: On the River Gran, Among the Quadi And so none of them can hurt me. No one can implicate me in ugliness. Nor can I feel angry at my relative, or hate him. We were born to work together like feet, hands, and eyes, like the two rows of teeth, upper and lower. To obstruct each other is unnatural. To feel anger at someone, to turn your back on him: these are obstructions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morphosyntactic Tagging with a Meta-BiLSTM Model - An Overview</title>
      <link>https://brongulus.github.io/blog/nnfl-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brongulus.github.io/blog/nnfl-paper/</guid>
      <description>(Subtitle: I had shingles, which is a painful disease.) This post contains a complete overview of the titled paper and provides a basic outline of related concepts. This paper aims to investigate to what extent having initial sub-word and word context insensitive representations affect performance.
Abstract  RNN leads to advances in speech tagging accuracy Zeman et al Common thing among models, rich initial word encodings. Encodings are composed of recurrent character-based representation with learned and pre-trained word embeddings1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Pathway to learning Japanese</title>
      <link>https://brongulus.github.io/blog/japanese-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brongulus.github.io/blog/japanese-guide/</guid>
      <description>JPod101 Add a nice collection of their videos and cheatsheet materials since most sources don&amp;rsquo;t really tell much about their actual content.
Hiragana  Why? All other basic textbooks have as requirement, romaji as a crutch that hurts later on Tofugu Guide Tae Kim Quiz  Katakana  Important thing to not delay learning it even when other sources say so. TODO Add sources and more info  Kanji + Grammar + Vocabulary Intro  Important step because after crossing the initial simple hurdle you&amp;rsquo;re presented with a mammoth choice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Notes</title>
      <link>https://brongulus.github.io/blog/random-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brongulus.github.io/blog/random-notes/</guid>
      <description>Chirping Bird Wall  &amp;ldquo;What seems to be the officer, problem?&amp;rdquo; :tf:
   Added first chirp and performed first squash while b8kd.
       step 1: eat and sleep better go outside and get sunlight. stand in the sidewalk outside of your shitty apartment, nobody will give a fuck. do not overcomplicate this, you and your mood are a product of the chemical compounds that you have chosen to fuel your body with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates &amp; A letter to self</title>
      <link>https://brongulus.github.io/blog/january-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brongulus.github.io/blog/january-update/</guid>
      <description>Hi there, it&amp;rsquo;s been a while. I doubt anyone&amp;rsquo;s reading these but I felt like writing something regardless.
So I&amp;rsquo;ve started going ham into kanji study again, (hopefully this time it&amp;rsquo;s more fruitful) and I think that now I&amp;rsquo;m getting the appeal of immersion and how beneficial it can be paired with the right amount of active recognition of what you&amp;rsquo;re recalling from your anki reps.
Coming to the S.M.A.R.T. (Specific, Measurable, Attainable, Realistic, and Time Bound) goals regarding japanese, let&amp;rsquo;s try to set some shall we?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Worklog</title>
      <link>https://brongulus.github.io/blog/worklog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brongulus.github.io/blog/worklog/</guid>
      <description>1 June 2022  [-] Leave Everything, Learn Python IUASCO Programming Perl DAS - From Scratch  9 February 2022  AnE Lab IIC Assignment DSA Catchup DSA Lab OOP 27 Jan Lecture  3 February 2022  Problem Formulation  2 February 2022  AnE Lab Submission (10 AM, 3rd Feb) SOP 2 Small Papers PowE Lab  31 January 2022  Chapter 2 T2 PowE Might be Test in AnE, so practice problems Prepare for IIC Tut too  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
